Finding Aid for Detroit Swedish Council records, 1963-1983
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Detroit Swedish Council records 1963-1983
Detroit Swedish Council.
2 linear feet
85140 Bd 2
Swedish-American cultural organization; scrapbooks, topical files, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by Mrs. Gunnar Karlström (donor no. 5693 )
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Detroit Swedish Council is a Swedish-American cultural organization.
The record group is comprised of scrapbooks, topical files, and photographs. The scrapbooks consist of clippings, programs, press releases and related material. Among the topical files is material relating to the visit to Detroit in 1976 of Carl XVI Gustaf, King of Sweden. The photographs are of the mortgage-burning at Augustana Evangelical Lutheran Church, Detroit, and photos of the visit of King Carl XVI Gustav of Sweden to the General Motors Proving Ground, Milford, Michigan.
Subjects:
Swedish Americans--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Augustana Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Automobile industry.; Churches--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.)--Churches.; Detroit Swedish Council.; General Motors Corporation.; Swedish Americans--Social life.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbooks
  - September 1963-June 1964 (Box 1)
  - July 1964-August 1965 (Box 1)
  - September 1965-March 1966 (Box 1)
  - June 1966-May 1967 (Box 1)
  - June 1967-November 1969 (Box 1)
  - December 1970-June 1972 (Box 1)
  - July 1972-1974 (Box 1)
  - 1977-1980 (Box 2)
  - 1980-1983 (Box 2)
- Other materials and topics
  - Visit of King Carl Gustaf, 1975-1976, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Gothenburg Cathedral Boys' Choir tour of the U.S., 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Swedish-American history, and prominent Swedish-Americans (Box 2)
  - Printed material, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1 album and 1 envelope (Box 2)